Simu Liu

Full Stack Developer

🔀 simuliu711@gmail.com 👂 Manseau, QC, Canada 🍙 apple0441 🛭 🔇 @pple711

Profile

Full Stack Developer with 8+ years of experience specializing in React and React Native development. He has created a wide range of apps, including diabetes tracking, event booking and ticketing, and budgeting. Simu Liu works in a clear and organized manner, ensuring that projects are well-planned before he starts programming. He contributes exceptional value as projects progress from start to finish while adding new features to existing products.

Professional Experience

Full Stack Developer, Trigent

03/2021 - 05/2023 | Remote

- Created a web application that allowed 75K users to search for nearby restaurants based on their location with 89% accuracy
- Worked with a team of 27 developers that created an e-commerce website using PHP, MySQL, and JavaScript within 3 months.
- Developed a responsive email template in HTML5 and CSS3 that oncreased the clickthrough rate by 78%, an improvement from previous years.
- Participated in code reviews of 100 developers' ensuring that all code complied 100% with coding standards & best practices.

Full Stack Developer, Webcrafters

02/2018 - 02/2021 | Warszawa, Poland

- Developed a brand new administration panel for purchasing agent business, which increased the customer service by 90% and improved the efficiency of operating by over 25%
- Increased customer satisfaction to 85% by creating database utilizing {H{5, PDO, and MySQL that streamlined tracking operations from creating, assigning and tracking truckloads.
- Developed 25 original e-commerce website and web applications, encompassing design, coding, testing and maintenance whilst supervising a team of 15 web developers.

Junior Web Developer, TapInfluence

12/2015 - 01/2018

Mountain View, United States

- Created a new landing page system which used a PostgreSQL database and an s3 bucket to drive the images and links for quick searches on the platform.
- Built the routing system on the search platform using react-router so that all searches were URL driven, allowing for saved and quick navigation.
- Built a simple user interface for use by the data science team to test out their new features without using URL or Postman.
- Extended internal data science tool to a separate, customer-facing platform for creating smaller, less focused influencer marketing campaigns using React, React-Apollo, and GraphQL.
- Learned React and Redux to work on the new search platform concept, the first foray into using React on the platform.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science,

Hong Kong University of Science and Technology(HKUST) ☑

09/2012 - 11/2015 | Kowloon, Hong Kong

Skills

English

MERN MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js	• • • •	MEAN ● ● ● MongoDB, Express.js, Angular.js, Node.js	• •
MEVN MongoDB, Express.js, Vue.js, Node.js	••••	Django ● ● ● (HTML, CSS, JS/TS, python)	• •
Database MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, NoSQL	••••	Cloud Firebase, Cloudflare, AWS	
Figma	••••	Others Python, C/C++, C#/.NET, WordPress, Laravel	• •
Languages			

Chinese